(
"ai_sub_version": "3.3.0",
"generated_at": "2026-07-15T01:41:14.467861",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Step Into Dreams
大空スバル 3rd Anniversary Live ぷれあです！
Oozora Subaru 3rd Anniversary Live "Pleiades!"
3周年ありがとう！これからもずっと君と一緒に！
Thank you for the 3rd anniversary! I want to be with you forever!
ホロライブに入る!!
I will join Hololive!!
オーディション会場
Audition Venue
ああ、いつものように
Ah, just like always,
過ぎる日々に 欠伸が出る
I yawn at the passing days.
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も
Crossing the bustling night, today again,
渋谷の街に朝が降る
morning falls upon the streets of Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような そんな気持ち
A somewhat empty feeling like that,
つまらないな でもそれでいい
it's so boring, but that's fine.
そんなもんさ これでいい
That's just how it is, this is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた
Unknowingly, I had been hiding
本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
my true voice. Let it resound, see?
見ないフリしていようとも
Even if I pretend not to see it,
確かにそこに居る
it is certainly right there.
ああ、感じたままに描く
Ah, drawing it just as I feel it,
自分で選んだその色で
with the colors that I chose myself.
眠い空気纏う朝に
In the morning clad in sleepy air,
訪れた青い世界
a blue world arrived.
好きなものを好きだと言う
Saying I like the things I like,
怖くて仕方がないけれど
I can't help but be terrified,
本当の自分に出会えた気がしたんだ
but I felt like I finally met my true self.
ああ、手を伸ばせば
Ah, the more I stretch out my hand,
伸ばすほどに遠くへ行く
the further away it seems to go.
思うようにいかない今日も
Even today, when things don't go as planned,
また慌たただしくもがいてる
I'm still struggling busily again.
悔しい気持ちもただ情けなくて涙が出る
Feeling frustrated and pathetic, tears start to fall.
踏み込むほどに苦しくなる
The deeper I step in, the more painful it gets,
痛くもなる
and the more it hurts.
ああ、感じたままに進む
Ah, moving forward just as I feel it,
自分で選んだこの道を
along this path that I chose myself.
重いまぶた擦る夜に
In the night when I rub my heavy eyelids,
しがみついた青い誓い
I clung to that blue vow.
好きなことを続けること
Continuing to do what I love,
それは楽しいだけじゃない
isn't just about having fun.
本当にできるか不安になるけど
I get anxious about whether I can truly do it,
ああ、何枚でも
Ah, no matter how many pages,
ほら、何枚でも
look, no matter how many pages,
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
I've kept drawing because I lacked confidence.
何回でも ほら何回でも
No matter how many times, look, no matter how many times...
積み上げてきたことが武器になる
...everything you've built up will become your weapon.
周りを見たって 誰と比べたって
Even if you look around, even if you compare yourself to others,
僕にしかできないことはなんだ
what is it that only I can do?
今でも 自信なんか無い それでも
Even now, I have no confidence. Yet, still...
感じたことない気持ち
This feeling I've never felt before,
知らずにいた想い
these thoughts I never knew I had...
あの日に踏み出して
Taking a step forward on that day,
初めて感じたこの痛みも全部
even all this pain I felt for the first time...
好きなものと向き合うことで
By facing the things I love,
触れたまだ小さな光
I touched a still tiny light.
大丈夫、行こう、あとは楽しむだけだ
It's okay, let's go, all that's left is to enjoy it!
全てをかけて描く
I'll risk everything to paint,
自分にしか出せない色で
with colors only I can express.
朝も夜も走り続け
Continuing to run through morning and night,
見つけ出した青い光
I've found that blue light.
好きなものと向き合うこと
Facing the things I love...
今だって怖いことだけど
It's still scary even now, but...
もう今はあの日の透明な僕じゃない
...I am no longer the transparent me of that day!
ありのままの かけがえのない僕だ
I am irreplaceable, just the way I am!
知らず知らず隠してた
The real voice I had been hiding...
本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
...let it resound, see?
見ないフリしていたって
Even if you pretend not to see,
確かにそこに、今もそこにあるよ
it's certainly there, it's still there even now!
知らず知らず隠してた
The real voice I had been hiding...
本当の声を響かせてよ、さあ
...let it resound, now!
見ないフリしていたって
Even if you pretend not to see,
確かにそこに、君の中に
it's certainly there, inside of you!
IRIS OUT
[Song: IRIS OUT]
ダメダメダメ脳みその中から
No, no, no, from the depths of my brain,
「やめろ馬鹿」と喚くモラリティ
my morals scream "stop it, you idiot!"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン
Darling, baby, darling,
半端なくラブ！ときらめき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
giddy with love, sparkling and floating philosophy!
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
Looking up so adorably it's killer,
なにがし法に触れるくらい
to the point where it's almost illegal.
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering madness, squandering it all before I knew it,
この世に生まれた君が悪い
it's your fault for being born into this world!
やたらとしんどい恋煩い
This terribly draining lovesickness,
バラバラになる頭とこの身体
my head and body are falling apart.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出てアイリスアウト
I love you gushes from my carotid artery, and iris out!
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with this feeling?
あばらの奥のざらめが溶けて ケロイドになりそう
The brown sugar deep in my ribs melts, turning into a scar.
どこ？バチが当たって 溺れ死にそう
Where? This divine punishment makes me feel like drowning.
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, you are the only correct answer in this world.
ダーリ ダーリ ダーリ ダーリ
Darlin', darlin', darlin', darlin'...
ひっくり返っても勝ち目ない
Even if things turn upside down, there's no chance of winning.
君だけルールは適用外
The rules don't apply only to you.
四畳半の密室はクローズしかない
This tiny room has no choice but to close.
かさ上げ崩壊
The buildup collapses!
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ
The Avada Kedavra you cast with a smile...
粉にして粉も申し訳ねえな
...turning me to dust, and sorry about the dust!
手を翳して 貫いて
Hold up your hand and pierce right through,
その弱点
that weak spot.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
Looking up so adorably it's killer,
なにがし法に触れるくらい
to the point where it's almost illegal.
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering madness, squandering it all before I knew it,
この世に生まれた君が悪い
it's your fault for being born into this world!
パチモンでもいい なんでもいい
A knockoff is fine, anything is fine,
今君と名乗ってる全て欲しい
I want everything that currently calls itself you.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出て
I love you gushes from my carotid artery...
アイリスアウト
...and iris out!
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with this feeling?
あばらの奥のざらめが溶けて ケロイドになりそう
The brown sugar deep in my ribs melts, turning into a scar.
どこ？バチが当たって 溺れ死にそう
Where? This divine punishment makes me feel like drowning.
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, you are the only correct answer in this world.
ダーリ ダーリ ダーリ ダーリ
Darlin', darlin', darlin', darlin'...
アイリスアウト
Iris out!
しゅっぴっぴー！スマホの充電足りてる？ホロライブ デバイス ReGLOSSのイエロー担当、音乃瀬奏、みずみずるうです！
Shuppippii! Is your phone's battery charged? From hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS, I'm the yellow representative, Otonose Kanade, also known as Mizumizuruu!
ということで、ステップ・イントゥ・ドリームズ始まりました！イェーイ！
And with that, "Step into Dreams" has begun! Yay!
今回はですね、オープニングにもあった通り、夢だったホロライブに入って、夢だった初めてのソロ...
This time, just like in the opening, after joining hololive which was my dream, my dream of having my first solo...
生誕ライブ、それでイェーイ！
Let's go to my Birthday Live, yay!
ちょっとめちゃめちゃに緊張しているんですけれども
I am incredibly nervous, but...
どうだった？群青のアイリスアウト
How was it? "Gunjou no Iris Out"
コメント欄どうだった？かっこよかった？
How was the comment section? Was it cool?
かっこよかったってきっと。まあこの後流れるんだろうな
It must have been cool, surely. Well, it'll probably flow in later.
かっこよかっただろ？
It was cool, right?
いっぱい褒めてください。
Please praise me a lot.
今回はですね、タイトルにもある通り...
This time, as you can see in the title...
もうステップが、もうハチャメチャにもステップが、ステップが、もうハチャメチャに多かったりですね
The steps are just... there are incredibly so many steps, so many steps!
あとは、やったことのないジャンルのダンスにも挑戦しちゃったりしていますので、お楽しみに！
And also, I'm challenging myself with genres of dance I've never done before, so look forward to it!
ハッシュタグは、こちらにあるハッシュタグ「#水宮スイ生誕祭2026」です！
The hashtag is this hashtag right here, #MizumiyaSuiBirthdayFestival2026!
スクショとか感想とかたくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you posted lots of screenshots and thoughts!
目指せトレンド！みんな、いっぱい通ってねー！
Aim for trending! Everyone, post lots!
この後はですね、ゲストパートにも行きたいと思っているの。ですが...
After this, I want to go to the guest part... However...
なんと、お祝いの映像が届いてるみたいなので、見てみましょう！
Wait, it seems a celebratory video has arrived, so let's take a look!
こっちかな？よし。
Is it this way? Okay.
なんだなんだ？
What is it, what is it?
キミを笑顔にご案内！南風の観光大使、にじさんじ所属、彩木の子の末っ子、シガリコだよ！
Guiding you to smiles! South wind tourism ambassador, Nijisanji-affiliated, youngest child of Ayakoki, I'm Shigariko!
水宮、お誕生日おめでとう！
Mizumiya, happy birthday!
きっと今、水宮は最高のライブをしていることでしょう。本当におめでとう！
Surely right now, Mizumiya is having the best live concert. Happy birthday!
本当はね、現地で直接お祝いがしたかったんですけど、どうしてもスケジュールが合わないということで...
Actually, I wanted to celebrate directly at the venue, but my schedule just didn't work out...
お祝いのメッセージ動画をね、今回送らせていただいております。
so I'm sending this celebratory message video instead.
水宮とはね、ロロメロとしてたくさんコラボして、プライベートとかでもテーマパーク行ったりとか...
With Mizumiya, we've collabed a lot as Lolomelo, and in private we've gone to theme parks...
映画行ったりとか、月一でお泊まりするくらい仲良くさせてもらってて...
movies, and even did sleepovers about once a month, we've gotten so close...
本当にいつもありがとう！
Thank you so much as always!
事務所が違うのにこんなに仲良くなれるなんて、もうめっちゃ嬉しいし...
Even though our agencies are different, being able to get this close makes me so happy...
いつも水宮に元気もらって支えてもらってます。
and Mizumiya always gives me energy and supports me.
これからもずっと友達！
Let's be friends forever!
いっぱい遊んで、いっぱい楽しいことしていこうね！大好きだよ！
Let's play a lot, and do lots of fun things! I love you!
それでは、シガリコでした！この後もライブ楽しんでね、頑張れー！
Well, that was Shigariko! Enjoy the rest of your live concert, do your best!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ということで、シガリコからメッセージが届きました。ありがとう、シガリコ。
So, a message arrived from Shigariko. Thank you, Shigariko.
こっちにいるかな？ありがとう、シガリコ！
Are you over here? Thank you, Shigariko!
いや、そう今回はね、ちょっとスケジュールが合わなくて、ちょっとリコの3Dにはね、ちょっと呼んでもらって、一緒に踊ったんですけど...
Yeah, this time our schedules didn't match. I was invited to Riko's 3D stream and we danced together, but...
スイのライブでは今回は踊れなかったけど、いつか一緒にまた踊ろうな。
we couldn't dance together in Sui's live concert this time. But let's dance together again someday.
ありがとうね、リコ！水宮頑張るよ！
Thank you, Riko! Mizumiya will do her best!
応援してもらったし、ちょっと次の曲にいこうかな？
Now that I've been cheered on, shall I move on to the next song?
次はゲストパートだから、誰が来るのかな？
Next is the guest part, so I wonder who will come?
このあとも、まだまだ続きます！そしてなんか告知もあるかもしれないので...
It's still going to continue after this! And there might be some announcements too, so...
最後まで楽しんでね！
enjoy until the end!
昔々の そのまた昔 とある貴族の 仲良しな兄弟
Once upon a time, long, long ago, there was a noble, friendly pair of siblings.
以下略称
(The rest is omitted)
「ちゃんとやれ！」
"Do it properly!"
じいやが呼ぶ 席につけ よーいどん！
The old butler calls out, "Take your seats! Ready, set, go!"
ナイフとフォークで応戦いたしますの
We go to battle with knives and forks.
だって僕らはブルジョアの 立派な立派な貴族様なんですですの
Because we are the bourgeoisie, great, great, noble children, aren't we?
ひれ伏せ愚民 君との違いを ヴァイヴァイスロイ 見せてやるぜ
Bow down, you commoners! I will show you the difference between you and us, Vice Viceroy!
おい まてまて また勝手にそんな 見抜けるような ハッタリかまして
Hey, wait, wait! You're acting on your own again, putting on a bluff like you can see right through it.
はーい はーい はいはい お兄様の仰せのままに（笑）
Yes, yes, yes, yes. As you wish, Brother (lol).
あーむかつくぜ！ まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, it makes me angry! It really makes me angry!
兄に対して 生意気な態度
You have such a cheeky attitude toward your brother.
時の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Raise the war cry! Ring the gong!
ケンカ勃発で宣戦布告
Conflict breaks out, declaration of war!
悪戯して 悪ノリして
Playing pranks, playing along,
ほらほら 煽っていくstyleで
Look, look, it's the provoking style.
“大安売り”買っちゃったら<
If you buy the "clearance sale",
毎度ありがとうで君の負け！
thanks as always, you lose!
狙い引き出しと煽り合いの駆け引きでキメる
Winning with a mix of poor drawers and teasing tactics.
兄の威厳見せるため飴と飴 火花散る散る両者の目と目
To show my brotherly authority, candy and candy, sparks flying between our eyes and eyes.
俺をだれだと思ってる くらえ！おれさまがルールブック▼
Who do you think I am? Eat this! I am the rulebook!
へたれじゃない ひよってない ちょっと勇気が足りないだけ
I'm not a coward, I'm not scared, I just lack a little courage.
さぁさぁみなさん お手をお手拝借 当たり前だろ 余裕しゃくしゃく
Come on, everyone, lend me your hands! It's obvious, isn't it? Relaxed and calm.
生まれながらにしてチート やべぇ煌めく 人生がスタート
I'm a cheat by nature. A sparkling life begins,
当然です 見てみな由緒はガチ勢
Of course it does. Look, the lineage is the real deal.
ハイ論破 ハイ論破 ハイ論破 もらってくぜ Vサイン
High rebuttal, high rebuttal, high rebuttal, I'll take that V-sign!
はい、はい、はい、はい、はい、はい！
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
はなまるよくできました
You did a wonderful job!
あーむかつくぜ まーじむかつくぜ
Ah, it's so annoying! Seriously annoying!
僕に向かって減らず口なんざ
Talking back to me like that,
とっておきを君に見舞え
I'll show you my special move!
報復！制裁！挑発しちゃって
Retaliation! Sanctions! You provoked me!
意地悪して一枚上手
Being mean and playing one card higher,
チャンスはもらってくスタンスで
I'm in a stance to take my chance.
痛恨ミス あっちゃっちゃー
A devastating mistake, oh dear!
お生憎様だね 君の負け
Too bad for you, you lose!
Yes!
だけど君 君だけが
But you, only you,
やあっ！ とぉっ！ やぁっ！ うっ！ やぁっ！ はっ！
Hiya! Toh! Ya! Urgh! Ya! Ha!
僕に似合いのライバル
Are a rival worthy of me!
とぉっ！ やあっ！ うっ！ とぉっ！ やぁっ！ はっ！
Toh! Ya! Urgh! Toh! Ya! Ha!
落ちるのも凹んでるのも
Falling down or feeling depressed...
うっ！ はっ！ やぁっ！ やぁっ！
Urgh! Ha! Ya! Ya!
調子狂わされるから
...it throws off my rhythm!
今宵もテメーとやいやいやいやい
So tonight as well, let's fight it out!
大体いつもそうやって... 年上のくせに！
You always do that... Even though you're older!
ハイ決定！
Now it's decided!
あーむかつくぜ まーじむかつくぜ
Ah, it's so annoying! Seriously annoying!
憎まれ口はお口をチャック
Zip your mouth if you have nothing nice to say!
鬨の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Battle cry, ring the gong!
次世代エンペラーはこの俺だ！
The next generation emperor is me!
悪戯して 悪乗りして
Playing pranks and going too far,
ほらほら煽ってくスタイルで
Look, look, provoking is my style!
1から100 いただきます
From 1 to 100, I'll take it all!
毎度ありーがとうで君の負け
Thanks for your patronage, you lose!
まさかの引き分け！？ ええーっ！
No way, a tie?! What?!
[Title: Lead Control]
この頃君が纏う お仕付け直しの季節の匂い
Lately, you've been wearing the scent of the 're-training' season.
強かな佇まいの割に脆いソコに触れるの
You touch the fragile parts despite your tough demeanor.
あぁ 怒らないでダーリン だってホントのことだもん
Oh, don't be angry, darling! Because it's the truth, you know.
体ばっかデカくなって 中身はガキだよね
Your body has grown big, but inside you're still a kid, right?
暴れないでドギー 私華奢な手だから
Don't rampage, doggie! Because I have delicate hands,
リードなんて気まぐれで パッと落としちゃうかも
I might just drop the lead on a whim.
だらし無い！意気地無い！ホント君は救えない！
You're sloppy! You're spineless! You're truly hopeless!
堕落に耽っちゃって ご愁傷様
It's a pity you're indulging in depravity.
夢が無い！糧も無い！くせに愛は欲しいの？
You have no dreams! You have no goals! Yet you want love?
なら3回まわってお手からワン！
Then turn around three times, give me your paw, and bark!
ルルル...
Lululu...
よーく聞いててダーリン 嫉み妬み人の企み
Listen closely, darling. Jealousy, envy, people's plots,
この世は罠だらけ ねぇ ずっとここにいて？
this world is full of traps. Hey, will you stay here forever?
ひれ伏してドギー 生まれもった才と脳で
Bow down, doggie. With the talent and brains you were born with,
全部を黙らせて 今日も稼いじゃう私の前に
silence everything and keep making money in front of me today.
あがいたって無駄 捌き部次第ね
Even if you struggle, it's useless, it depends on my handling,
私は知らなかった頃の日々に戻りたい？
Do you want to go back to the days before you knew me?
walk into a trap 無知な babe 侵す drug
Walk into a trap, ignorant babe, drowning in drugs.
もうワタシを知らなかった頃のキミは戻らない...
You won't be able to return to the version of you that didn't know me...
だらし無い、意気地無い、ホント君は救えない
You're sloppy, you're spineless, you're truly hopeless.
どこにも行けないね
You can't go anywhere.
くだらない！果てしない！こんな広い世界で
How boring! How endless! In this vast world,
私に堕ちていく君が好き！
I love that you're falling for me!
夢が無い！糧も無い！くせに愛は欲しいの！
You have no dreams! You have no goals! Yet you want love!
なら3回まわってお手からワン！
Then turn around three times, give me your paw, and bark!
ルルル...
Lululu...
[Title: Cyberpunk Dead Boy]
お書きになったそんな音楽は 現在使われておりません
The music you wrote is currently not in use.
意味わかんねぇ
I don't get it at all.
意味わかんねぇ！
I don't get it at all!
どうせ誰も聞いてないさ
No one is listening anyway.
音楽なんてセンス・ファッション
Music is just sense and fashion.
おんなじクラブ、ステージ、退場はない
Same club, same stage, there is no exit.
どうせ何も伝えてなんか無いさ
Nothing's being communicated anyway.
ネットでトーク、トーク、トークで売名
Talking, talking, talking on the net to self-promote.
あの娘気取って、おどけて、最低、グッナイ
Posing like that girl, playing the fool, the worst, good night.
あいつだって、どいつもだって、そいつもだって、どうしたって、もう大渋滞
That guy, everyone, this guy, whatever they do, it's a huge traffic jam.
それでもあっちこっちそっちぽっち、満足？
Still, here, there, everywhere, are you satisfied?
ZとH、猿も欲しがる
Z and H, even monkeys want them.
ワンチライフ、欲しいの？
Do you want a once-in-a-lifetime life?
意味とかどうだっていいよ
Meaning doesn't matter.
歌詞とか、どうでもいいので
Lyrics or whatever, I don't care,
ノれるのをください
just give me something I can groove to.
さぁ、皆で笑いましょう
Come on, let's all laugh together.
芸術よりスノッブでしょう
It's more snobbish than art, isn't it?
バイラスに酷い代償
A terrible price to pay for going viral.
じゃあどうすんの？
Then what are you gonna do?
それでいいんだっけ？
Was that really okay?
頭は空回り、死んでいく
My head is spinning in circles, dying away.
Selling myself instead
ふざけるな
Don't mess around!
バイバイ バズメロディ
Bye bye, buzz melody.
疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり
Doubt it, it's mostly lies.
バケモノ
Monsters!
幻想でも 理想でもいい
Illusion or ideal, either is fine.
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what you wanted to sing?
形骸でもいい
Even a mere shell is fine.
ほら 嘘じゃない
Look, it's not a lie.
お金や理想で満たす前に
Before filling it with money or ideals,
バケモノ
Monsters!
覚醒せよ 子供たちよ
Awaken, children!
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what you wanted to sing?
意味分かんねぇ
I don't get it at all!
お立ち台に立つそんな音楽は現代に使われておりません
Such music that stands on the podium is not used in the modern era.
ポップスのヒットソング聴いてもう一度お書き直しください
Please listen to pop hit songs and rewrite it.
あーもう、ハイカラスタ、バカばっか、うっさいわ、ふん
Ah, geez, high collar stars, nothing but idiots, shut up, hmph.
どいつもこいつもそいつもあいつも 意味わかんねぇ
That guy, everyone, this guy, whoever they are, I don't get it!
あいつだって、どいつもだって、そいつもだって、どうしたって、もう大渋滞
That guy, everyone, this guy, whatever they do, it's a huge traffic jam.
それでもあっちこっちそっちぽっち、満足？ ZとH、猿も欲しがる
Still, here, there, everywhere, are you satisfied? Z and H, even monkeys want them.
ワンチライフ、欲しいの？意味とかどうだっていいよ
Do you want a once-in-a-lifetime life? Meaning doesn't matter.
歌詞とか、どうでもいいので、ノれるのをください
Lyrics or whatever, I don't care, just give me something I can groove to.
さぁ、皆で払いましょう
Come on, let's dispel it all.
芸術よりスノッブでしょう
It's more snobbish than art, isn't it?
バイラスに酷い代償
A terrible price to pay for going viral.
じゃあどうすんの？
Then what are you gonna do?
それでいいんだっけ？
Was that really okay?
頭は空回り、死んでいく
My head is spinning in circles, dying away.
Selling myself instead
ふざけるな
Don't mess around!
バイバイ バズメロディ
Bye bye, buzz melody.
疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり
Doubt it, it's mostly lies.
バケモノ
Monsters!
幻想でも 理想でもいい
Illusion or ideal, either is fine.
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what you wanted to sing?
このままじゃ到底 終われない
There's no way it can end like this.
欲しいのはきっと金じゃない
What we want is surely not money.
バケモノ
Monsters!
覚醒せよ 子供たちよ
Awaken, children!
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what you wanted to sing?
ふざけるな
Don't mess around!
バイバイ バズメロディ
Bye bye, buzz melody.
疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり
Doubt it, it's mostly lies.
バケモノ
Monsters!
幻想でも 理想でもいい
Illusion or ideal, either is fine.
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what you wanted to sing?
嘘でもいい ほら 嘘じゃない
Even a lie is fine, look, it's not a lie.
お金や理想で満たす前に
Before filling it with money or ideals,
バケモノ
Monsters!
覚醒せよ 子供たちよ
Awaken, children!
僕の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what I wanted to sing?
意味わかんねぇ
I don't get it at all!
せーの
Ready, set...
りおちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Rio-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！おめでとう！やったー！
Thank you! Congratulations! Yay!
何歳になったわけ？
How old did you turn?
20歳バージョン2！
20 years old, version 2!
ありがとう、ありがとう
Thank you, thank you.
あんた主役でしょ
You're the main character, right?
そう、今日の主役ですから、水無世は
That right, because Minase is today's main character!
ちょっとみんなに一言言ってね、去ってもらおうかなって
I want everyone to say a quick word before they leave.
一人ずつ記念、ほら、りおにほら、愛をね、一言
One by one, show some love to Rio, a quick word.
一言、一言、誰から、ほら
A quick word, a quick word, who's first, come on.
いいよ、じゃ、うち
Okay, then, me.
ママだよ
I'm your mom.
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
もうほら、ちゃんと記念、次
Come on, next, properly.
もう、変な人いて怖かったでしょ
That weird person was scary, wasn't it?
ママだよ
I'm your mom.
違うよ、違う違う！
No you're not, no, no!
ほら、残りの二人も
Come on, you two remaining as well!
俺がママだ！
I'm the mom!
別に芸能事務所をさ、なんか、あれじゃないのよ、芸人じゃないのよ
We're not some entertainment agency... we're not comedians!
これからも あるなお姉ちゃんに頼ってね
You can keep relying on your big sister Aruna from now on!
お姉ちゃんと思ってんの？本当に
Do you really think of her as a big sister?
おかしいよ、おかしいよ
That's weird, that's weird.
ほら、ちゃんとほら、りおに、最後に、りおにね
Come on, properly to Rio, at the end, to Rio, right?
うちらスビビの仲やんか
We're close friends in SubiBi, aren't we?
そうね
That's right.
だから、せーのって言ったら何言うかわかるよな？
So, if I say "Ready, set...", you know what to say, right?
わかる！いくよ！
I know! Let's do it!
せーの！スビビ最下位！
Ready, set... SubiBi is in last place!
待って待って！何で自分らで最下位って言うの！
Wait, wait! Why did you say we are in last place?!
間違えた、間違えた！
I made a mistake, I made a mistake!
せーの！スビビ最強！
Ready, set... SubiBi is the strongest!
いえーい！ポーズ取って、ポーズ！
Yay! Strike a pose, pose!
撮れた？大丈夫？
Did you get it? Are we good?
おっけーおっけー！
Okay, okay!
ありがとうね、みんな！
Thank you, everyone!
バイバーイ！コボちゃん頑張って！
Bye-bye! Good luck, Kobo-chan!
コボちゃん良かったよ！
You were great, Kobo-chan!
ありがとう！バイバーイ！頑張って！
Thank you! Bye-bye! Good luck!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
なんかうるさかったな。頑張るか。よし。
They were a bit noisy. Let's do our best. Alright.
くだらない問いの結末で 僕らは生まれ落ちて
As the result of a silly question, we were born into this world,
呼吸さえ強いられているけれど
Even though we are forced to even breathe.
きれいな言葉並べて 醜さに蓋をして
Arranging beautiful words, covering up the ugliness,
自分を愛せないまま、裸足だな。ずっと
Without being able to love myself, I'm barefoot. Always.
くだらない嘘を吐くたび 甘い色こぼれ落ちた
Every time we tell a silly lie, sweet colors spill out.
ガラスの瞳が綺麗で
Your glassy eyes are so beautiful,
君のその目蓋のように 優しい人になってさ
I want to become a gentle person, just like your eyelids,
そんな僕を愛したいんだよ
And learn to love myself.
私の呼吸に終わりがあること
Knowing that my breath will one day come to an end,
君の声、覚えている
I still remember your voice.
生まれては消えていくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away, we just repeat that over and over.
僕らがもしまた会えたらだなんて思ってた
I kept thinking, what if we could meet again?
生まれては消えていくくだけの 青白い波に名前をつけることに
Giving a name to the pale blue waves that only rise and fade,
意味はなかったのかな、なんてさ
Maybe there was no meaning to it after all.
他愛ない忙しさに 積み木で遊んでいる
In our trivial busyness, we play with building blocks,
崩れるその日を待ってる
Waiting for the day they collapse.
澄みきった夜の静寂が 君の頬の赤色で
The silence of the clear night is stained with the red of your cheeks,
もうすぐ桜が咲くんだろう
Cherry blossoms will surely bloom soon.
僕らの呼吸に意味がなくても
Even if our breaths have no meaning,
二人はまた恋をする
The two of us will fall in love again.
生まれては消えていくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away, we just repeat that over and over.
そして君も夜の海に帰っていくんだろう
And you, too, will probably return to the night sea.
生まれては消えていくくだけの 青白い波に名前をつけることに
Giving a name to the pale blue waves that only rise and fade,
囚われている
We are trapped in it.
ねえ、覚えているかな
Hey, do you remember?
いつかの春 of 朝に 桜の木の下で
On that spring morning under the cherry blossom tree,
約束したこと
The promise we made.
思い出も君の名前も いつしか失ってしまって
Even the memories and your name will eventually be lost,
僕もいつかこの海と一つになるんだろう
And I, too, will one day become one with this sea.
君のいない冬の空気が 僕の頬をさする、その痛みさえ愛していたい
The winter air without you caresses my cheek—even that pain, I want to love it.
生まれては消えていくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away, we just repeat that over and over.
僕らがもしまた会えたらだなんて思ってた
I kept thinking, what if we could meet again?
生まれては消えていくくだけの 青白い波に名前をつけることに
Giving a name to the pale blue waves that only rise and fade,
意味はなかったのかな、なんてさ
Maybe there was no meaning to it after all.
こうして冬が終わって
And just like this, winter ends,
青い春が来る
And a blue spring arrives.
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? Oh troubled child of man,
UNLUCKY? 人ならざる者も
Unlucky? And those who are not human,
BE HAPPY! まず目指せよ
Be happy! First, aim for it!
生きているんだし
Since you are alive,
目を逸らした過去も
even the past you turned your eyes away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future too,
カウンセリング やれやれ
counseling, oh dear,
古今東西 ピースピース
through all times and places, peace, peace!
UNHAPPY?
UNLUCKY?
BE HAPPY!
UNDEAD!
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ
Hey, hey, hey,
なんだかどうして
for some reason, why is it?
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting somehow.
触れられない
Untouchable,
過去の自分 自分 自分と
with my past self, self, myself,
もうとっくに死んでる
who is already long dead,
透明な亡霊と対決
confronting a transparent ghost.
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep within the innocent and painful memories,
残念
What a pity.
もう居ないのにあれ？
You're not there anymore, wait, why?
そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Do you prefer that? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分？ナンセンス
Is it my current self that is being seen through? Nonsense.
消えないレッテル
A label that won't go away,
要はコンプレックス
in short, a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It's like I'm possessed,
巻き付いたまま
wound around me,
まだ離れない在りし日の自分
still not letting go, my self of bygone days.
死んじゃいない
You're not dead,
お前とお前の連鎖
you and your chain.
生きていることは変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be satisfied with wallowing in unhappiness.
幸せになろうとしないなんて嘘だ
Saying you won't try to be happy is a lie!
この世 この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre, bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
What will come out next, a demon or a snake?
出会って違ってやっと始まる物語
Meeting, differing, at last the story begins.
さあ人か化物か 古今東西ピースピース
Now, human or monster? Through all times and places, peace, peace!
Past & Future can't change the past
Past and future, can't change the past.
Past & Future run for the future
Past and future, run for the future!
何だかどうして
For some reason, why is it?
未来になんぞ何の
Why is it that I have no hope
期待もできない
cannot expect anything
ような気がして
feeling like...
もう随分生きてる
I've lived for quite a while now,
既視感とテンプレで食傷
fed up with déjà vu and templates.
素敵な出来事の気配もない
There's no sign of anything wonderful happening.
残念
What a pity.
積んだ経験の因果
The causality of accumulated experience,
形骸化された信じたくない真実
rendered formal, truths I don't want to believe,
退屈な進化
boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいの
In short, I want stimulation,
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I'm tired of it, I'm used to it.
整っていくガイダンス
Guidance getting organized,
増えるコンプライアンス
increasing compliance,
蓋されていくみたい
it feels like I'm being shut in,
退屈して
being bored...
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
That, this, and that all taste the same.
死んじゃいない
You're not dead,
お前とお前の連鎖
you and your chain.
何時の世も過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
At all times, past and future are in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Foolishly fulfill the act of being alive,
目指せハッピーエンド
aim for a happy ending!
死んじゃいない
You're not dead,
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking to you!
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であるなら
Don't give up on happiness, if you are human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to suffering and enduring it is...
死んでるも同然 屍のアンデッド
no different from being dead, a zombie-like undead.
UNHAPPY?
UNLUCKY?
BE HAPPY!
まず目指せよ
First, aim for it!
生きているんだろ
You are alive, right?
不幸に浸るも
Wallowing in unhappiness,
幸せになるのも
and becoming happy too,
そう全部全部お前だ
yes, it's all up to you!
古今東西 森羅万象 ピースピース
Through all times and places, all creation, peace, peace!
Past & Future can't change the past
Past and future, can't change the past.
Past & Future run for the future
Past and future, run for the future!
人の在る処に何時も憂い事
Where people are, there is always sorrow,
有象無象 化物ばかりの物語
a story full of rabble and monsters.
ちょっとやんちゃで
A little mischievous,
にこっと元気な
smiling and energetic,
ちらっとスマイル
a quick smile,
アイドル！
idol!
毎日をもっと楽しくしたい
I want to make every day more fun,
だんじょん With Adventure!
dungeon with adventure!
ひらひらスカートも
Even my fluttering skirt,
ちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
I can wear it perfectly!
だからもっともっと好きになって（もいいよ）
So you can like me more and more (that's fine too!)
いいよ一緒に
That's fine, together...
大空に飛び立とう！
let's fly away into the big sky!
光るスターライト 輝きの中でも
Shining starlight, even within the brilliance,
強い煌めき
a strong sparkle,
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you?
おっけー！ すばるチャンネル！
Okay! Subaru Channel!
Everyday, night and day, みんなで！
Every day, night and day, everyone together!
ブルーな気持ちにツバっとかけつけ
Rushing in to clear away your blue feelings,
お助けしちゃうヒーロー！
I'm the hero who'll come to your rescue!
弱いハートはいらないから
Since a weak heart is no use,
つよつよで行きましょう！
let's go forward, strong and bold!
ハラハラな水際で
At the thrilling water's edge,
ドキドキのときめきタイム
it's time for heart-pounding excitement!
いつでもおいでよ
Come visit anytime,
年中パラダイス
it's a year-round paradise!
カウントダウン
Countdown,
曇り空吹き飛ばそう！
let's blow away the cloudy skies!
あがれ！サンシャイン！
Rise! Sunshine!
どんな暗闇の中も眩しく照らす
Brightly illuminating even the deepest darkness.
君に見つけてもらえた
That you were able to find me...
それだけでもう運命なんだ
...in itself is already destiny.
もっとずっと道は続いていく
This road will keep on going forever,
夢に向かって
heading toward our dreams.
一緒に生きてくれるかな
Will you live this life with me?
その手取って走れ
Take my hand and run!
連れていくよみんなで！
I'll take everyone along with us!
ささやく 恥ずかしいけれど
I whisper, even though it's embarrassing,
伝えたい想い 今なら言える
but I can say these feelings now.
君のエールが力になるよ
Your cheers become my strength,
いつも元気を分けてくれて
always sharing your energy with me.
頑張っていけるんだ
I can keep doing my best,
笑って過ごせるんだ 本当に
and truly spend my days smiling.
ありがとうのこの気持ちを
These feelings of gratitude,
歌え！
sing them out!
シャイン！
Shine!
どんな輝きの中も強くきらめき
Sparkling strongly amidst any radiance.
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1ミリでも伝わればいいな
I hope it transmits to you, even just a millimeter.
もっとずっと道は続いていく
This road will keep on going forever,
夢に向かって
heading toward our dreams.
一緒に生きてくれるかな
Will you live this life with me?
その手取って走れ
Take my hand and run!
連れていくよみんなで！
I'll take everyone along with us!
君とかけるすばる！
Running with you, Subaru!
すばる先輩ありがとうございました！後半もよろしくします！
Thank you so much, Subaru-senpai! Please enjoy the second half!
コボ、がんばれー！
Kobo, do your best!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy birthday!
誰かのための痛み？
Someone's pain for someone else?
僕の願い、やがて散り散り
My wish, eventually scattered...
椅子取りゲームみたい
...like a game of musical chairs.
それでも、息をしていくしかない
Still, I have no choice but to keep breathing.
まだ、聞こえるか？
Can you still hear it?
とっくのとうに詰まった呼吸
Breath already blocked long ago.
関係ない、うるせえわ 自分だけが聞こえてる
Doesn't matter, shut up. Only I can hear it.
安定なんて捨てた
I threw away stability.
もう、すべてを振り切るスピードで
Now, at a speed that cuts through everything!
その瞬間まで、足掻いて
Until that moment, struggling,
ただ、脳絞って、今、見えるとこまで
just squeeze your brain, now, to where you can see.
この瞬間を飲み干して、また踊って
Drink down this moment, and dance again.
見たことないもの、見せて
Show me something I've never seen before.
「君の代わりはいない」
“No one can replace you,”
もし、誰かが否定しても
even if someone denies it.
僕の代わりはいない
No one can replace me,
違うことない、僕の目覚まし
undoubtedly, my awakening.
誰かの祈る手を払った痛み
The pain of brushing away someone’s praying hands,
どこから漂う悪意の兆し
where does the sign of drifting malice come from?
正しさに息を潜めた怒り
Anger hidden in righteousness,
それすらも僕に残った光
even that light remained in me.
誰かの熱を奪う感覚
The sensation of stealing heat from anyone,
逃げる気はとうにないぜ、全く
no intention to run away, not at all.
この手が震えるほどの錯覚が、起こした摩擦
A hallucination that makes this hand tremble, caused friction.
まだ、見えてるか？
Can you still see it?
とっくにスポットライトを奪った
Already took away the spotlight.
関係ない、うるせえわ
Doesn't matter, shut up.
自分だけに聴かせてる
I'm only letting myself hear it.
安定なんてやめだ
No more stability.
もう、すべてを振り切るスピードで
Now, at a speed that cuts through everything!
この瞬間だけ、足掻いたって意味ないぜ
Struggling in this moment is meaningless.
今、見えるとこまで
Now, to where you can see.
第六感で惹きあって、また踊って
Drawn by the sixth sense, dance again.
見たことないものを、見せて
Show me something I've never seen before.
今をブチ抜いて！
Pierce through the present!
もう、ノンストップで脳、擦り切れるまで
Already nonstop, until the brain is worn out.
この瞬間を飲み干して、また踊って
Drink down this moment, and dance again.
見たことないもの、見せて
Show me something I've never seen before.
さあ、この瞬間を飲み干して
Now, drink up this very moment...
また踊って 尖った生意気見せて
...keep on dancing, and show your sharp audacity!
連れていかれるように
As if being swept away,
踏み出した暗い街へ
I stepped out into the dark streets.
tell me what you need
後追う背中は
The back I chase from behind
黒く染まってた
was dyed completely black.
wait, hold up
悪党？それとも正義？huh?
Are you a villain? Or justice? Huh?
やりがい searching 馬鹿みたい
Searching for purpose feels so foolish.
目の前の問題は it's too much now
The problems right in front of me are too much now.
後回しでもまあ良いじゃん
It's fine to just put them off, right?
人生の意味 結局何？
What is the meaning of life anyway?
不安定な日々に裏返る声
My voice cracks in these unstable days.
あれこれ言ってる間に
While fussing over this and that,
姿を消し去った君は誰？
who are you, who suddenly vanished?
曖昧な世界が変わった
The ambiguous world changed
あの日の
on that day.
ど派手に響かせた声が
The voice that echoed so flashily
まだ今も鳴り止まない
still won't stop ringing even now.
紅の夜に心奪われて
My heart is stolen by the crimson night.
このどうしようもない感情に
Within these helpless emotions,
君を映してた
I kept reflecting you.
増えてく影を追い
Chasing the multiplying shadows,
気づけば遠い街で
before I knew it, I was in a distant town.
引き返し元通りになるのには
To turn back and return to normal,
もう遅かった
it was already too late.
wait, hold up now
SOS 逃げ道がないの
SOS, there's no way out!
え、ちょ待って
Wait, hold on...
how is it my fault?
レフト、ライト
Left, right,
ステップからの
from the steps,
get down に見せかけて clap
pretending to get down, then clap!
からかっておいて立場は対等？
Teasing me like that, and we're supposed to be equals?
助けてやって何その態度
I saved you, and that's the attitude you give me?
不満の中で生まれる依存症
An addiction born out of discontent,
垣間見えるのは愛
a glimpse of what might be love.
退屈な世界が変わった
The boring world changed
あの日の
on that day.
ど派手に響かせた声が
The voice that echoed so flashily
まだ今も鳴り止まない
still won't stop ringing even now.
紅の夜に心奪われて
My heart is stolen by the crimson night.
このどうしようもない感情に
Within these helpless emotions,
君を映してた
I kept reflecting you.
このどうしようもない感情に
Within these helpless emotions,
君を映してた
I kept reflecting you.
はい、はい腹から声出して
Yeah, yeah, scream from your gut!
そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまんせ
Or else you'll end up having a painful time!
勝敗かけた歌合戦
A singing battle with victory on the line,
枯れそうな地声で
with a natural voice about to wither,
まだ歌うのさ
I will keep on singing!
ど派手に響かせた声が
The voice that echoed so flashily
まだ今も鳴り止まない
still won't stop ringing even now.
紅の夜に心奪われて
My heart is stolen by the crimson night.
このどうしようもない感情に
Within these helpless emotions,
君を映してた
I kept reflecting you.
(はい、はい腹から声出して)
(Yeah, yeah, scream from your gut!)
(そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまんせ)
(Or else you'll end up having a painful time!)
紅の夜に心奪われて
My heart is stolen by the crimson night.
このどうしようもない感情に
Within these helpless emotions,
君を映してた
I kept reflecting you.
Always, always on me
関係、探って
Probing our relationship,
嗚呼 ごめんねって
saying "Ah, I'm sorry"...
意味がないね
...doesn't mean anything.
バグだらけアルゴリズム 満ち足りない
A bug-filled algorithm, never satisfied.
じゃあ どうなりたい？
So, what do you want to become?
そっと 暴いて
Exposing it gently,
二重で 被る面相
wearing a face covered in double layers.
優しい言葉 並めて
Lining up gentle words,
ふたり お揃いに甘えて
both of us relying on each other.
演じて 魅せてるのは誰のために
Who are you acting and performing for?
ただ 泣いたように 笑っていたんだ
I was just laughing as if I were crying.
all eyes on me
偽りの deepfaker
A deceptive deepfaker.
i なんて わかっちゃいないんだ
I don't even understand the "I."
all eyes on me
いつのまにか deepfaker
Unconsciously becoming a deepfaker.
Always, always on me... deepfaker
重ね重ね お詫びします
I apologize repeatedly,
気持ちのない 口癖
a habit of speaking with no feeling.
優しさに ズルさも 吐き違えて
Confusing kindness with deceit,
重ね、重ねた 嘘の吐息だけで
with only layer upon layer of lies in my breath,
満たされるマスク
the mask is satisfied.
また淡々と取り繕っている
Still indifferently keeping up appearances,
本当の顔は誰のためで
for whose sake is my real face?
ただ苦しくなるね
It just becomes painful, doesn't it?
お揃いの名前の前 前の前
Before our matching names...
ただ泣いてないで 笑っていたいよ
I don't want to just cry, I want to be laughing.
All eyes on me いつまでも Deep Faker
All eyes on me, forever a Deep Faker.
愛なんてわかっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand things like love at all.
All eyes on me いつの日か Deep Faker
All eyes on me, someday a Deep Faker.
脱いでみたい
I want to take it off.
演技でもないなら
If it's not even an act, then...
それだって勝手 よせなはれ
That's also selfish, so cut it out.
胸に秘めている Deep Faker
The Deep Faker hidden in my heart.
また泣いたように笑っていたんだ
Again, I laughed as if I were crying.
All eyes on me 偽りの Deep Faker
All eyes on me, the false Deep Faker.
愛なんてわかっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand things like love at all.
All eyes on me いつの間にか Deep Faker
All eyes on me, before I knew it, a Deep Faker.
All eyes on me, All eyes on me, Deep Faker
All eyes on me, Deep... Deep... Deep Faker
みんな、どうでしたか？
Everyone, how was it?
いやぁ、今回はですね、あの
Well, this time, you see...
ハウスダンスにね、初めて挑戦したんですけれども
I tried house dancing for the very first time,
あの、2ヶ月で、あの、詰め込んで、踊れてましたか？
and had to cram it all in 2 months. Did I manage to dance it?
いや、めっちゃ頑張ったってコメントが書いてくれてるんだろうなぁ、いやはや
I'm sure the comments are saying, "You worked so hard!" Gosh...
でね、あの、「波に名前をつけること、僕らの呼吸に終わりがあること」って曲では
And also, in the song "Naming the waves, our breathing having an end,"
リフトをしたり、あの、クルクルね、回って
doing lifts and spinning around...
あれも初めてやりました。踊れてたら嬉しいね！
I did that for the first time too. I hope I danced it well!
いや、ゲストのね、ハル先輩、レイドちゃんともイケイケに踊って
And I danced so coolly with the guests, Haru-senpai and Reid-chan!
つるぎ先輩とは、憧れのつるぎ先輩と2人きりでドキドキタイムしちゃったり
With Tsurugi-senpai, the Tsurugi-senpai I admire, we had a heart-pounding time alone together!
るな氏とゆい先輩となずちゃんとは、もう対決しまくって
I faced off like crazy against Runa-shi, Yui-senpai, and Nazu-chan,
るぜせんとべにちゃんとは歌って
sang with Ruze-sen and Beni-chan,
フォルテとはカッコよく、いやぁ
and with Forte, it was so cool. Man...
ゲストパートもたくさんね、素晴らしいのがあったんじゃないでしょうか？
We had so many wonderful guest parts, didn't we?
ということで、皆さん、何か忘れてませんか？
So, everyone, aren't you forgetting something?
ねぇ、皆さん。枢の休憩タイムもね、もうそろそろ終わらないといけない。
Right, everyone? Su's break time has to end pretty soon.
よし、立つか。うわぁ、はい。
Alright, let's stand up. Whoa, okay.
ということで、なんとですね、こんな感じで言うのもなんですが、
So, actually, it's a bit sudden to say it like this, but...
新曲が出ます！イェーイ！
A new song is coming out! Yay!
初のオリジナル楽曲！フフフフフ！
My very first original song! Uhuhu!
あ、やばい、体が疲れた。よいしょ、よいしょ。
Ah, oh no, my body is tired. Heave-ho, heave-ho.
はい、ということで、作詞・作曲・編曲は、サトダユーリさんに作ってもらいました！
Yes! So, the lyrics, composition, and arrangement were done by Satoda Yuri-san!
ありがと、ドンドパフパフ ドンドパフパフ！
Thank you! Dondopafupafu dondopafupafu!
はい、このあと、すぐMV公開がね、この配信が終わったあとあるのですが、
Yes, right after this stream ends, the MV will be released!
リダイレクトで飛びます。そして、デジタルリリースは、今日の0時からなので、
We will redirect you there. And the digital release starts at midnight tonight,
たくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです！
so I'd be happy if you listen to it a lot!
じゃあ、ちょっと早速なんですけど、その新曲をお披露目しちゃおうかな？
Now, without further ado, shall I perform the new song?
いや、どんな楽曲なんだろう？気になるな。どんな楽曲なんだろう？行きます！
I wonder what kind of song it is. I'm so curious. What kind of song could it be? Here we go!
うみゃうみゃ うみゃうみゃ
Umya-umya, umya-umya!
うにゃうにゃ うにゃうにゃ
Unya-unya, unya-unya!
うみゃうみゃ うにゃうにゃ
Umya-umya, unya-unya!
どろろん？ きゅるるんっ
Dororon? Kyururun!
あ～そろそろごはんの時間かな？
Ah, is it about time for dinner?
あ、でもでも、やっぱやっぱ 家から一歩も出たくな～いっ!!
But then again, after all, I don't wanna take a single step outside!!
こんな時はそうだ！ 飯テロの動画！
In times like this, yes! A food-porn video!
「説明しよう！極限までお腹を空かし美味しくいただくのだ！」
"Let me explain! You starve yourself to the limit, then eat deliciously!"
めんどいめんどいマジめんどいわ
So annoying, so annoying, seriously annoying!
けっきょくぐだぐだ時間溶けたわ
In the end, I just wasted time slacking off.
ぴろんぴろん5回目アラーム
Beep, beep, that's the fifth alarm!
コンビニいこー
Let's go to the convenience store!
わちゃわちゃはちゃめちゃ奇想天外
Noisy, crazy, and unpredictable!
ドタバタてんやわんや見逃せない
An uproar, a hectic mess, you can't miss it!
ピンチだってちょいのちょいのちょいで
Even a pinch is solved in a jiffy!
てやっ！ てやっ！ そりゃっ！ そりゃっ！ 万事解決☆
Teyah! Teyah! Soryah! Soryah! All is resolved☆
うみゃうみゃうにゃうにゃ おいしくなぁれ☆
Umya-umya, unya-unya, become delicious☆
あれもこれもお皿全部食べたいな
I want to eat this, that, and the whole plate!
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃハピネスライフ
Chomp chomp, umya-umya, happy life!
食べて寝て遊んでまた食べる
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again!
ぺこぺこぺこぺこはらぺこじゃ
Total, total empty stomach!
うみゃうみゃうみゃうまく生きません
Umya-umya, life doesn't go smoothly!
ひとまずごはんをおなか1ぱい食べさせてよ
For now, let me eat my fill of food!
うみゃうみゃ
Umya-umya!
うにゃうにゃ？
Unya-unya?
うみゃうにゃ！
Umya-unya!
お〜い天気〜
Oh hey, weather!
あの雲ソフトクリームみたい！
That cloud looks like soft-serve ice cream!
あ、あっちはわたがし！
Ah, that one's cotton candy!
雲ってふわふわで美味しそう
Clouds look so fluffy and delicious.
人生で1回は食べてみたいよね〜
I'd love to try eating one once in my life~
じゃない！
Wait, that's not it!
しんどいしんどいマジしんどいわ
It's exhausting, exhausting, seriously exhausting.
現実逃避何度もしちゃうわ
I escape reality over and over again.
妄想空想頭が暴走
Delusions, fantasies, my head is running wild.
カツオ食べたーい！
I want to eat bonito!
だらだらだらだら怠惰全開
Lazing around, lazing around, laziness at full throttle!
ネガティブ思考もご愛嬌です
Even my negative thinking is part of my charm!
世界だってぽいぽいのぽいで
Even the world, I'll just toss it away, toss-toss!
えいやっ！えいやっ！とりゃっ！とりゃっ！
Hiyah! Hiyah! Take that! Take that!
ねじ伏せちゃうぞ
I'm gonna knock it down!
うみゃうみゃうみゃうみゃお腹空いたら
Umyau-myau-myau-mya, when my tummy rumbles...
突撃！隣の晩御飯！
Charge! Neighbors' dinner!
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃ幸せタイム
Munch-munch, umyau-mya, happy time!
食欲で生きてます
Living on pure appetite!
だからどうかお願い
So please, I beg of you!
このおなかを満たして神様！
Fill this belly of mine, oh God!
食べたい！
I want to eat!
寝てたい！
I want to sleep!
難しいことは何も考えたくない
I don't want to think about anything difficult.
あとあと、みんなでお菓子パーティもしたーい！
And and, I also want to have a sweets party with everyone!
うみゃうみゃうみゃうみゃ美味しくなぁれ
Umyau-myau-myau-mya, become delicious!
あれもこれも全部食べたいな
I want to eat this, that, and everything!
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃハピネスライフ
Munch-munch, umyau-mya, happiness life!
食べて寝て遊んでまた食べ
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again!
ペコペコペコペコ腹ペコだ
So hungry, so hungry, I'm starving!
うみゃうみゃうみゃ美味しく召しませ
Umyau-myau-mya, bon appétit!
ひとまずごはんをお腹いっぱい食べさせて！
For now, let me eat till my tummy is full!
まだ足りない
It's still not enough!
もっともっと食べさせて！
Let me eat more and more!
新曲、どうだった？かわいかったでしょう？
How was the new song? It was cute, right?
かわいいっていうコメントがたくさん見えます。ありがとね。かわいい、かわいい、ありがとう。知ってる、知ってる。
I can see lots of comments saying "cute." Thank you. "Cute, cute..." Thank you! I know, I know.
ということでね、新曲のタイトルは「うみゃうみゃハッピーらいふ」でしたー！
So, yes! The title of the new song was "Umyau-mya Happy Life"!
今回はちょっと可愛い感じにしたので、次はなんかカッコいい感じにしたいなーみたいな、まあ何も決まってないんですけどね。
Since we went for a cute vibe this time, next time I'd like to do something cool, maybe? Though nothing's decided yet.
ということで、新曲が終わったからって帰ろうとしてない？
So, just because the new song is over, you aren't thinking of leaving, are you?
ねえ、なんか忘れてるよね、みんな？ということで！
Hey, you're forgetting something, right, everyone? So, with that in mind...!
グッズ！
Merch!
水宮すう誕生日記念2026のグッズを早速1つずつ見ていこーう！
Let's check out the Mizumiya Su Birthday Celebration 2026 merch one by one right away!
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
オーロラアクリルパネル！
The Aurora Acrylic Panel!
公式イラストレーターのぶくろてママに描いてもらいました！ありがとう、ママ〜！
It was illustrated by my official illustrator, Bukurote-mama! Thank you, Mama!
ふわふわのね、お部屋でお茶会みたいなね、可愛い感じになっております！
It has a cute look, like having a tea party in a fluffy room!
もうママが天才すぎるので、ぜひ買ってください！
My mama is just such a genius, so please buy it!
2つ目は、こちら！
The second one is this!
ハート型缶バッジ！
Heart-shaped Can Badge!
こちらはね、もう可愛いお顔がドアップになっております、多分。
This one has a close-up of my cute face, probably!
ハート型の缶バッジは初めてなんじゃないかなと思っているので、
I think this might be my first time making a heart-shaped can badge,
ぜひこちらも買ってみてください！
so please be sure to get this one too!
3つ目が、こちら！
The third one is this!
おくるみすぅぬいぐるみ！
The Swaddled-Su Plushie!
こちらもね、すぅちゃんがおくるみに入っています！
This one also has Su-chan wrapped up in a swaddle!
ま、なんか、すぅを結構おくるみに入れてくれてる方も見たりとかしたので、
Well, since I've seen some people drawing Su wrapped in swaddles and stuff,
もしかしたらみんな、こういうのを待っていたんじゃないかなと思って作りました！
I thought maybe everyone was waiting for something like this, so I made it!
衣装はね、キービジュアルの衣装で、
The outfit is the same as the key visual,
ちょっと小さめのぬいぐるみを作ってみました！
and I made it a slightly smaller plushie!
4つ目は、こちら！
The fourth one is this!
れきおー推し活ショルダーバッグ！
The Rekio- Oshikatsu Shoulder Bag!
こちらにはですね、さっきのハート型のね、缶バッジとか、
In this bag, you can put the heart-shaped can badges
おくるみぬいぐるみが入れられるようになってます！
and the swaddled plushie we just saw!
はい、天才！天才！天才！
Yes, a genius! Genius! Genius!
ということで、こちらも一緒にぜひ、れきおーのね、推し活のバッグに入れて、
So, please put them together in your Rekio- oshikatsu bag,
すぅをね、あの、可愛く持ってください！よろしくね！
and carry Su around cute-style! Thank you!
他の推し様もぜひ入れてみてね！
And feel free to put other favorites in there too!
5つ目が、こちら！
The fifth one is this!
ボイス！
Voice Pack!
タイトルは「すぅと、お茶会」。
The title is "Tea Party with Su."
こちらはね、おうちで、優雅な、優雅な、
This one is about spending an elegant, elegant,
優雅な！アフタヌーンティーを楽しむすぅと、一緒にね、
elegant afternoon tea time at home with Su,
いっぱい楽しんじゃうボイスとなっております！
and enjoying lots of fun together in this voice pack!
最後に、フルセット！
And lastly, the Full Set!
直筆サイン入りのオリジナルカードと、ASMRボイスがついてきます！
It comes with an autographed original card and ASMR voice tracks!
ちょっとね、すぅちゃん...
With a bit of Su-chan...
おうちに お呼ばれしちゃったみんながね
Everyone who was invited over to my house,
ちょっと距離近めでね ASMRボイスが
at a slightly close distance... The ASMR voice
こんな感じで、まあ、ちょっと、なんか、適当なんですけど
is kind of like this, well, it's a bit random,
まあ、そんな感じのボイスになっております！
but it's that kind of voice!
こちら！数量限定じゃない！
This is not limited in quantity!
ので、焦らずにみんなゆっくりで大丈夫です！
So there's no need to rush, you can all take your time!
グッズは、22時10...ん？
The merch will go on sale at 10... huh?
22時10分から販売開始です！
It will go on sale starting at 10:10 PM!
直筆のサインとかもね、全部、もう何もかも数量限定じゃないので、
Even the hand-signed ones, everything is not limited in quantity,
あの、ずうちゃんのサインもあの、付いてきますのでね、フルセットを買ったら！
so Zuu-chan's signature will be included if you buy the full set!
皆さん、よろしくお願いします！ぜひ！
So everyone, thank you in advance! Please!
買ってね！
Buy it, okay?
いっぱい買ってね！
Buy lots of it, okay?
はい！ということで、以上、みにみあによるグッズ紹介でした！
Yes! So, that was the merch introduction by Mini Mia!
はーい！ということで、みにみあありがとう！
Alright! So, thank you, Mini Mia!
なんか結構ミスってたな。まあみにみあだからね。
She made quite a few mistakes. Well, she is Mini Mia.
すうじゃないから。仕方ないか！
She's not Zuu, so I guess it can't be helped!
ということで、誕生日の3Dライブはどうだったでしょうか！
Anyway, how did you like my birthday 3D live?
憧れのホロライブに入ってから、みんなにいっぱい応援してもらってここまで来れました！
Since joining my dream Hololive, I've received so much support to get this far!
みんなに、少しでもね、かっこよかったとか、
If you thought I was even a little bit cool,
すうのこと応援しててよかったって思ってもらえてるととっても嬉しいです！
or if you felt glad to support Zuu, I would be so happy!
MVはこのあとすぐ公開で、リダイレクトで飛ぶので、チャンネルはそのままでよろしくお願いします！
The MV will release right after this, and you'll be redirected, so stay on this channel!
ということで、みんな！これからもよろしくね！ありがとう！
With that, everyone! Please keep supporting me! Thank you!
じゃ、ばいばーい！またねー！
Well then, bye-bye! See you later!
ずうりすへ / ずうを見つけて、応援してくれてありがとう！
To Zooris, / Thank you for finding and supporting Zuu!
そのおかげでみんなにエネルギーをあげる / ピカピカな存在、自慢のみにみあになれるよ！
Thanks to that, I can give everyone energy / and become a shining presence, a Mini Mia you can be proud of!
これからもコツコツがんばっていくので / 応援してね！
I'll keep working hard bit by bit, / so please keep supporting me!
ずうががんばれるのはずうりすのおかげ！
Zuu is able to do her best because of Zooris!